<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Embedded particles on BornAgain</title>
    <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Embedded particles on BornAgain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cylinders in Born Approximation</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/cylinders-ba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/cylinders-ba/</guid>
      <description>Cylinders in Born Approximation Scattering from a monodisperse distribution of cylinders using the Born approximation.
 The cylinders are all identical with radii and heights equal to $5$ nanometers. The wavelength is equal to $1$ $\unicode{x212B}$. The incident angles are equal to $\alpha_i = 0.2 ^{\circ}$ and $\phi_i = 0^{\circ}$. There is no substrate (particles are embedded in the air layer), hence no refraction, hence no distorted waves, hence DWBA boils down to regular Born approximation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cylinders in Distorted Wave Born Approximation</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/cylinders-dwba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/cylinders-dwba/</guid>
      <description>Cylinders in Distorted Wave Born Approximation Scattering from a monodisperse distribution of cylindrical particles using the Distorted Wave Born Approxiamtion (DWBA).
This example is similar to the simulation Cylinders in Born Approximation, but now the particles sit on top of a substrate. Therefore incoming and scattered waves are distorted by reflections from the substrate surface, as described by the DWBA.
 The distribution of cylinders is monodisperse with heights and radii of $5$ nm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cylinders with size distribution</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/size-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/size-distribution/</guid>
      <description>Cylinders with size distribution Scattering from a polydisperse distribution of cylinders in Born Approximation.
 The average radii and heights of the cylinders are equal to $5$ nm. The radii of the cylinders vary according to a normal distribution with a standard deviation $\sigma$ equal to $0.2$ times the average radius. The wavelength is equal to $1$ $\unicode{x212B}$. The incident angles are equal to $\alpha_i = 0.2 ^{\circ}$ and $\phi_i = 0^{\circ}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two types of cylinders with size distribution</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/size-distribution2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/size-distribution2/</guid>
      <description>Two types of cylinders with size distribution Scattering of a polydisperse distribution of two types of cylinders.
 The simulation is performed using the Born approximation, i.e. there is no &amp;ldquo;substrate&amp;rdquo; layer. The sample is made of polydisperse cylinders of two different sizes: $R_1 = H_1$ and $R_2 = H_2$, where $R_i$ and $H_i$ are the radius and width of cylinder of type $i$. There are 95% of cylinders of type $1$ and 5% of cylinders of type $2$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotated Pyramids</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/rotated-pyramids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/rotated-pyramids/</guid>
      <description>Rotated Pyramids Scattering from a monodisperse distribution of rotated pyramids.
This example illustrates how the in-plane rotation of non-radially symmetric particles influences the scattering pattern.
 The sample is made of pyramids deposited on a substrate. Each pyramid is characterized by a squared-base side length of $10$ nm, a height of $5$ nm, and a base angle $\alpha$ equal to $54.73^{\circ}$. These particles are rotated in the $(x, y)$ plane by $45^{\circ}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cylinders and Prisms</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/cylinders-and-prisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/cylinders-and-prisms/</guid>
      <description>Cylinders and Prisms Scattering from a mixture of cylinders and prisms without interference.
 The sample comprises a substrate on which are deposited, in equal proportion, cylinders and prisms. All particles are made of the same material. Each type of particle has the same orientation. The cylinders are $5$ nm high and $5$ nm in radius. Each prism is $5$ nm high with an equilateral triangular base, whose side length is equal to $10$ nm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All available form factors</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/all-formfactors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/embedded-particles/all-formfactors/</guid>
      <description>All available form factors Scattering from all individual particle&amp;rsquo;s shapes implemented in BornAgain.
 For each figure, one particular shape is used.  The dimensions of the object are chosen only in order to get a characteristic signature of the form factor in the same range of values for the output angles.
 The simulation is run using the Born approximation. There is no substrate and also no interference between the scattered waves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>