<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Complex Shapes on BornAgain</title>
    <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Complex Shapes on BornAgain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Core shell nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/core-shell-nanoparticles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/core-shell-nanoparticles/</guid>
      <description>Core shell nanoparticles Scattering from cuboidal core-shell particles.
 The sample is made of core-shell particles whose outer and inner shells are boxes with dimensions $L_1 = W_1 = 16$ nm, $H_1 = 8$ nm and $L_2 = W_2 = 12$ nm, $H_2 = 7$ nm, respectively, where $L_i$, $W_i$ and $H_i$ are the length, width and height of box $i$. The smaller box is positioned so that the centres of the bottom faces of both particles coincide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hexagonal Lattices with Basis</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/hexagonal-lattice-with-basis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/hexagonal-lattice-with-basis/</guid>
      <description>Hexagonal Lattices with Basis Scattering from two layers of spheres distributed along a hexagonal close packed structure.
 The sample is made of spherical particles deposited on a substrate. These $10$-nanometer-radius particles are distributed along a hexagonal close packed structure:  each layer is generated using a two-dimensional hexagonal lattice with a lattice length of $20$ nm and its $a$-axis parallel to the $x$-axis of the reference Cartesian frame. the vertical stacking is done by specifying the position of a &amp;ldquo;seeding&amp;rdquo; particle for each layer: $(0,0,0)$ for the first layer and $(R,R,\sqrt{3}R)$ for the second layer, $R$ being the radius of the spherical particle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Particle Form Factor</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/large-particles-formfactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/large-particles-formfactor/</guid>
      <description>Large Particle Form Factor This example demonstrates, that for large particles (~$1000$ nm) the contribution to the scattered intensity from the form factor oscillates rapidly within one detector bin and analytical calculations (performed for the bin center) give completely a wrong intensity pattern. In this case Monte-Carlo integrations over detector bin should be used.
The simulation generates four plots using different sizes of the particles, (radius $=10$ nm, height $=20$ nm) or (radius $=1$ $\mu$m, height $=2$ $\mu$m), and different calculation methods: analytical calculations or Monte-Carlo integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Form Factor</title>
      <link>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/custom-formfactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scgmlz.github.io/BornAgain-website/documentation/sample-models/complex-shapes/custom-formfactor/</guid>
      <description>Custom Form Factor Scattering from a monodisperse distribution of particles, whose form factor is defined by the user.
 This example shows how users can simulate their own particle shape by implementing the analytical expression of its form factor. The particular shape used here is a polyhedron, whose planar cross section is a &amp;ldquo;plus&amp;rdquo; shape with a side length of $20$ nm and a height of $15$ nm. These particles are distributed on a substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>